Contact

+966534856751 (Work) gunjanrt@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ gunjantrivedi04 (LinkedIn) www.alj.com (Company)

Top Skills

Business Development Strategy Retail

Languages

Arabic (Limited Working)
Kannada (Limited Working)
English (Full Professional)

Certifications

Managing Data Analysis, John Hopkins University

The Data Scientist's Toolbox, John Hopkins University

IBM Blockchain Foundation for Developers

People Analytics, Wharton

Building a Data Science Team, John Hopkins University

Honors-Awards

District Champion, Swimming
District Captain, Table Tennis
Winner of Times of India Painting
Competition

Winner at Inter College IT & Business Quiz Competition

Member of Gujarat State Delegation to MOSCOW for Table Tennis

Gunjan Trivedi

Weaver, New Strategic Business Partnerships | Spearheading Business Overhauls | Tech Driven Revenue Growth Leader | Business Head | Product Innovator | Retail | eCommerce | Data Strategist | Career Coach

Jeddah

Summary

I am a Decisive, Empathetic, Agile, Juggernaut

I have cherished various roles in my career in Product Management / Category Management, Store Operations, Regional & National Business Operations, IT in Retail and ECommerce domains, for Grocery/FMCG and Consumer Electronics, with more than 10 years of P&L ownership

I have discovered the following about myself in this short journey

I can quickly extend my career learnings across various functions and create value as a class Strategic Business Unit – this SBU is on course to cross GMV run rate of SR 100 million + / annum in less than 12 months of inception

- I can influence and negotiate C Suite Leadership and Shareholders for an intrapreneurial venture
- I am a risk taker with quick decisive action acumen!
- I have a knack for stitching together win-win strategic partnerships with Government Entities, Financial Institutions, Charities,
 Developers and Corporates for B2B and B2C businesses to leverage opportunities

I love to accelerate overhaul of distressed business units / business channels, which matter – I scaled a business unit from SR 80 mn / annum to SR 245 mn / annum in 24 months with record profitability

- I can drive value in Business Channels and Products by developing the right product / offering portfolio mix
- I have a track record of branding a Business Unit and also a Product, to engage the target customer base most effectively

- I can successfully conceive, strategize and launch complex projects like rebranding of a B2C business both online and offline and rolling out ERP
- I can sweat the same customer by weaving more than one business models to serve his needs; I can do this for B2B and B2C business channels
- I can successfully address customer pain areas through Products and Services solutions

I can scale multiple Product Categories optimally

- I led more than 100 suppliers across general merchandise categories to deliver the business objectives

I can lead, coach, motivate and drive diverse culture teams towards the integrated company goals with finesse – I can come over language and culture challenges both in India and Saudi Arabia comprehensively

I love Swimming, Story Telling and Data Science

I am always looking for turning around Business Units - do not hesitate to get in touch if you have any in your mind

Professional Skills

Intrapreneurship | Strategic Planning | Product Management | Mentoring | Conflict Resolution | Leadership

Domain Skills

Python |OracleBI | Tableau | Salesforce | Oracle CX | Impact | Data Science | Machine Learning | Oracle Retek | Retail Pro

Experience

Abdul Latif Jameel
Head of Strategic Business Unit - Tajheez
October 2019 - Present (11 months)
Jeddah, Makkah, Saudi Arabia

I incubated Tajheez as a Strategic Business Unit, conceptualized and setup by me to align Abdul Latif Jameel Electronics products with Ministry of Housing Initiatives in line with Vision 2030.

It is an intricate fabric of carefully chosen strategic partnerships across the Housing Eco System(National Housing Company, Ministry of Housing, Developers, Contractors, Financial Institutes and Charities), based on the core premise of providing Solutions to Citizens and not just Products for their needs.

It is based on 4 Pillars of Business

- 1 Financial Solutions
- 2 After Sales Solutions
- 3 Services / Diagnostics Solutions
- 4 Product Solutions

It is a unique proposition with a hybrid omni-channel business model which a blend of B2B and B2C solutions across Retail Stores, Online using Ecommerce and digital partnerships with the strategic stakeholders

It is now GMV SR 100mn+ business entity

Abdul Latif Jameel
Deputy General Manager, Retail & Corporate
January 2015 - August 2019 (4 years 8 months)
Jeddah, Makkah, Saudi Arabia

I led the turnaround of Omnichannel Business Unit from a stage of closure to a phase of exponential growth with overall responsibility of the P&L

I strategized growth of Cash, Installment, DIgital and Corporate business channels optimally

I increased per sq meter revenue by 100% in a span of 2 years, increased the revenue per employee by > 100% by innovative campaigns around our product categories without disrupting alternate business channels of the company

I recommended and administered re-branding of the omni-channel business to facilitate greater customer connect and better representation of our products I spearheaded the transition of the Business Unit from near 80% expat to 20% expat in the employee strength, while delivering key business metrics

Landmark Group

7 years 11 months

Head of Operations, E Max, Central Saudi Arabia January 2013 - December 2014 (2 years)

Riyadh

I led the revenue growth for Central Region by more than 50% in a span of two years

Oracle Retail Applications(RMS, SIM, POS, CO, BO, ReIM) February 2012 - January 2013 (1 year)

Bangalore

Played a critical role Functional Consultant/Business Analyst/Retail Domain Expert to transition the Organization to Oracle ERP from legacy systems

Regional Operations Manager November 2010 - January 2012 (1 year 3 months) Pune

Administered licensing activities for expanding into western India

Led the strategic partnerships between SPAR and various service providers

Recruited, trained and led more than 600 staff

Launched two best-in-class Hypermarkets in a span of 6 months

Store Business Manager October 2009 - November 2010 (1 year 2 months) Bangalore

Overhauled store operations within 12 months in terms of process optimization and optimal manpower allocation
Scaled revenue by 50%
Improved bottomline by 300 basis points

Buyer | Category Manager | Business Manager | Product Manager February 2007 - October 2009 (2 years 9 months)

Bangalore

Key Achievements -

Identified, led and mentored more than 100 vendors across General Merchandise to deliver the business objectives of Revenue Growth and Bottomline Optimization

Launched Private Label Dew Nonstick-ware

Increased Sales Per Sq Foot by more than 100% with-in 12 months through promotions and range building for Utensils, Plastics & Crockery Categories

Brought about Margin Per Sq Foot increase of more than 200% in 15 months for categories of Stationary, Toys and Furniture organically with same trading area - spearheaded the category overhaul

Key Deliverables for the Categories:

Overall Profitability of the Categories, Assortment planning, Layout/Planogram, Inventory Management; strive to achieve negative working capital in the categories, Pricing, Promotion Planning, Vendor Management, Local & International sourcing

Hindustan Coca-Cola Beverages Pvt Ltd Summer Intern April 2006 - June 2006 (3 months) Bengaluru, Karnataka

Led route optimization for Bangalore Region which resulted in 35% reduction in TAT to service the outlets

Genesis Information Technology, Vadodara Software Professional June 2004 - April 2005 (11 months)

Summer Training on 'Distribution Channel Optimization', with; , Bangalore
A project on 'Agricultural and Processed Food products Export
Development Authority (APEDA)', with Technopak Advisors Pvt. Ltd.
Online Management Information System implementation, with Gujarat State
Fertilizers Corporation, Gujarat

Education

Indian Institute of Management Bangalore Strategy Consulting · (2019 - 2019)

International Institute of Information Technology Bangalore

Post Graduate Diploma in Data Science, Business Analytics · (2020 - 2021)

INDUS BUSINESS ACADEMY - IBA, BANGALORE

PGDBM, Marketing + IT · (2005 - 2007)

Dharmsinh Desai University

Bachelor of Engineering - BE, Computer Engineering · (2000 - 2004)

Tejas Vidyalaya

HSC, Science · (1985 - 2000)